I recently joined uh Xbox like in
Microsoft because it was part of
>> You did not. You went from Xbox to Xbow.
You changed one letter.
>> Yeah.
>> Best part of Viking when you can just
you know critical think.
[Music]
One of the things we love the most as
hackers, right, is people or industries
that are just pushing the boundaries of
what are possible. They're on the
bleeding edge and they're asking the
tough questions and pushing industries
forward, right? And that I just want to
be clear is why we've had Threat Locker
on as a sponsor of this podcast for so
long is they are doing that for the zero
trust industry. constantly coming up
with innovative solutions to push the
industry forward. And the latest one
that they've come up with is threat
locker user store, right? Because one of
the main problems with zero trust is
everything has to be validated on the
last mile, right? There has to be a
response team that's approving
applications as it's coming through. Um,
and that's burdensome to the user. And
so they decided to preload that compute,
right, and and approve a set of
applications in advance that threater
users can uh utilize to accomplish their
business goals. For example, if they're
trying to download Sketchy PDF file
reader.exe,
instead the user store will give them
instant access to Adobe Acrobat saying,
"Hey, why don't you open it with this
one instead?" Um, rather than having to
go through the whole response team. It's
instantaneous. It's quick. It's
pre-loaded. That's another way that
Threat Locker is pushing the industry
forward.
Sup, hackers. Got the This Week in Bug
Bounty segment for you. First up is Yes,
We Hacks live hacking event at Null Con
uh in Berlin. Okay. Uh, this is
September 4th through 5th and maybe if
you guys haven't been able to land one
of those exclusive live hacking event
invites, this is a good opportunity for
you cuz they're running a live hacking
event that is open to all Ncon Berlin
attendees. Okay, so you can just pop in,
pop some shells with other hackers, have
a blast. The live hacking event
experience is really unparalleled, guys.
It really is. So, um, if you're at
Nulcon, you're definitely going to want
to hop in on this. Uh, I I love the how
to participate here. They're like,
"Okay, log in to the Nulcon Berlin Wi-Fi
and then log into your Yes, we hack
account and boom, you'll see the Nulcon
Berlin program uh featured at the top
right." So, they've got something set up
that's cool there. Um, so that's
definitely something you're want to
check out if you're going to be at
Nulcon. Um, next up, oh, what is this?
Next up on the list is uh Bug Bounty
Village. There's a talk by your boy
Justin Gardner. Wow, how did that get
there? Um, no, seriously. The the agenda
for Bug Bonnie Village is super stacked
this year. You've got Golden, you know,
doing something. You've got me, you've
got the expo team, you've got Hadex,
you've got Ben, uh, you've got the
voices from the front lines of all the
uh, triagers and stuff like that,
managing book bounty programs. Um, we
got another panel with me and Nah and
Insider PhD. Um, the list goes on and
on, guys. It's an amazing lineup. Um,
also I'm only going to be around uh
Defcon on the 8th, right after I give
this talk. I'm going to be hanging
around at Bug Money Village pretty much
the whole day, giving out swag left and
right. Um, so definitely come and see me
on the 8th if you want to if you want to
catch up. Um, we're going to be giving
out a ton of of t-shirts. Reszo will
also be around, so I think he'll be
around for longer, so you can catch him
as well. But if you see me, come up, say
hi. I'd love to talk to you. Um, all
right. Uh, next up on the list is uh,
yes we hack again with a in conjunction
with talkyp pony Kaido special number
two advanced features and customization.
There's been a lot of really awesome
content coming out featuring Kaido
lately and this is a great uh, YouTube
video that covers some of the plugins
that you should be aware of including
uh, quick SSRF matrix uh, yes we Kaido
Pamfinder and more. Um, so there's been
a ton of movement in the Kaido space
lately. So, uh, if you're looking to
kind of keep keep up with that, this is
a great place to do it. Or if you want
to really deep dive, uh, Kaido, like
really deep dive, there's an amazing
video that just came out recently, uh,
AMR sec. Okay, this guy's been putting
out some awesome content. This is a
one-hour uh video covering uh how a
Kaido masterass essentially how to uh
use everything in Kaido. Okay, so you've
got like uh all of the plugins, you've
got environment, variables, automate,
workflows, uh HTTP history, filtering,
all of that, right? So, this is one of
the most comprehensive videos that's
been put out on Kaido just yet. Um he he
beat me to the punch on it because I
wanted to do something just like this as
well. Um so, definitely check this out
and if you're looking to take the dive
into Kaido. All right, last but not
least, our boy Iugulo, uh, full-time
hunter, uh, hacker extraordinaire, did a
write up for Bug Crowd. I met this guy
at GRHack and we hung out the whole time
and I just had a blast. So, shout out to
my boy. He also has a great blog, by the
way. Um, but he did a write up for uh,
bug crowd called access control versus
account takeover, what bug bounty
hunters need to know. uh and it covers a
lot of great content uh on you know
understanding the nuances of various
vulnerabilities like account takeover
IDORE that sort of thing. So um there's
definitely a lot of bugs in here that
you're going to want to be aware of. Um
so check this out uh if you're if you're
interested in uh you know understanding
the nuances of these these
vulnerabilities. All right, that's it.
Let's go back to the show.
All right, man. Our pillow fort has been
built. our our audio is dialed in and um
we are glad to have you on the pod
today, Diego. Thanks for for coming and
represent uh you know yourself as a
talented hunter and expo this crazy AI
that we're seeing all over the bug
bounty space.
>> Yeah, thank you guys for inviting me.
It's a pleasure to be here.
>> Of course, man. Um well, you all know
the drill. The drill is as soon as you
come on Critical Thinking podcast,
you've got to drop a bug. So, um,
Diego's got a bug for us and, you know,
a bug that he's going to talk about, um,
you know, representing Expo in this
specific, uh, situation because we're
competing with Expo on the leaderboards,
right? So, we got to have, you know,
Diego and Expo giving their their, um,
their bug write up. So, um, let's do
let's do yours first, which looks like
it's an account takeover, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Right. Yeah. So, uh, this
one was an account takeover through like
different multi-step bypasses that we
went through. Um I want to give kudos to
uh my teammate Black Amba from Spain
because this was found in one of the uh
ambassadors world cup. Um so basically
to give some context there was a company
that has some sort of identity
management system. Um so there was an
endpoint to validate the current user
token and retrieve access uh scope
information. Uh so there was something
like uh slappi/b5/
token. uh it was a post request and you
have to provide like the client ID in
the body. Uh so the first thing that we
saw is that if you do some sort of API
downgrade uh from B5 to B2, you could uh
modify the post to a get and the request
was working anyways. Nice.
>> So was uh that was the first step that
we we found.
>> Then we saw as well that the endpoint
has JSON P support. So when you add the
callback parameter in the request the
response will be wrapped into a JSON key
structure and uh so the the response can
be kept from a cross domain origin. Um
but then we found that of course not
origins were allowed and that was like
the third step. So there was like some
sort of refer base access control um and
the server was only returning the data
if the request comes from one of those
um domains.
Uh so that was like a complex step
because of course you need to find an
XSS or something like that to change
that in one of those uh whit listed
domains. We had like four or five I
remember. Um so the last step from this
bug was finding an XSS through uh an
Adobe uh experience manager uh
dispatcher bypass. So we saw that one of
those domains was using AM and we I know
I'm really used to this kind of uh
bypasses. So with us with that the
dispatcher bypass uh we could exploit an
XSS and then um do the full PC to get
the the account take over. So it was
like a crazy chaining between like all
five um steps. It was like a really cool
one.
>> Dude, Joseph, like I don't know, man. I
when you hear a bug like this, doesn't
it just like I don't know. I know you're
not as much of a client side guy as I
am, but this just like is just heaven.
>> No, no. I have extreme respect for any
kind of like anytime there's multiple
things you have to bypass like multiple
either protections or just multiple like
features or gadgets you have to chain
together. It definitely gets my blood
going. So
>> yeah, dude. It's great. Okay. So So this
actually is interesting um Diego because
it sounds you know you said there's
there's JSON P you you can wrap in it,
right? And so then it actually it sounds
like a little bit like it's like an
XSSI, right? where um and which is sort
of a dead bug bug class due thanks to
like same site um default cookies. But
what you guys um did here is you chained
that with an XSS I assume on a same site
subdomain, right? And then you were able
to include that script cross origin but
same site and then grab the the access
token out of there. Is that right?
>> That's right. Yeah. When I read your
little summary, I thought that that the
entire chain was in AM and just the way
that you listed out the different
things. So, I thought it was going to be
like a traditional refer bypass like you
know like an unescaped like dot or
something and the refer check so you
could like register a new domain to do
the bypass and that all of it was
actually happening in AM. But now I
understand like that it was actually on
a different system but then you all use
an access in AM to then make the
request. Very cool.
>> Yeah. Beautiful.
>> That's right.
>> Beautiful man. I love I love these
chains and I love the um you know
>> because these chains are going to be
resilient to AI finding them eventually.
>> Oh yeah, there we go. Let's see. Let's
get some takes on that. Um but I think
this really highlights as well um
collaboration, right? One of the big big
pros of collaboration, right? Like I
don't know the details of this specific
environment, but often when I've been
working with a team, you know, I'll have
this, you know, API downgrade JSON P
refer, you know, problem, right? And
then some other person's like, "Oh,
well, I've got this, you know, crappy
little XSS over here that, you know,
doesn't really do anything beside, you
know, maybe on like a CDN domain or
something like that." And then you chain
those two things together to to get
account takeover. Is that is that what
happened in this scenario? Did multiple
people find different pieces or
>> Yeah, exactly. So, this was basically
found originally by Black Gamba like the
the API downgrade and the JSON pag. So
then he talked to me um like we used few
uh bypass this kind of uh AM I know like
multiple dispatcher bypasses some of
them really like I think that they are
not known yet uh some of them have been
fixed doing the during the way uh but
some still work nowadays
>> well Diego you know the CTBB podcast is
the best place to drop those sort of
things if you're so inclined
>> I think we I can disclose that because
actually I cannot find like a lot of
them right Now, I think almost all of
them are fixed now. So,
>> all right. Awesome.
>> Awesome.
>> We'll we'll loop back around to that.
I'm definitely going to take you up on
that. It is my favorite thing about
doing this podcast when, you know, we
get some some new research released
right on the pod. And I love to bring
people on and like interview them and
dive deeper into the research that they
do. But when it's released here on the
pod first, that's just when I'm like,
this is why I started this podcast, you
know, like. So, excellent job, man. What
a great bug. Um, all right. So now
you've established your your um you know
worth as a hacker here. Now let's talk a
little bit about expo. So you had a
>> well well let's actually intro Diego
fully like similar similar to Justin and
I. You're a hacker one ambassador,
right? But you are an ambassador from
Spain. Where do you live?
>> In Madrid.
>> In Madrid. Cool. And what's your
favorite team?
>> Uh we are Madrid. Of course.
>> Real Madrid. Nice. Cool. Yeah. No, I
just wanted to ask that for fun. Um
yeah, so Diego has been around the live
hacking event circuit for a while.
Justin and I have seen him at at plenty
of live hacking events. Um but uh yeah,
so tell us how Spain's been doing in the
Ambassador World Cup, Diego.
>> Oh my gosh, dude.
>> Yeah. So um so far has been like really
good. We we managed to win for second
year in a row. So So yeah.
>> Yeah, they're pretty great. Yeah,
>> we got knocked out at what, final eight?
Did US South or whatever US team we were
on this year get knocked out in like
final eight or final four or something?
>> I don't know, man. You know, and that's
something that I kind of want to get a
take on from you, Diego, as somebody who
I mean, it looks like your team
obviously went really hard for the
Ambassador World Cup is um you know, the
Ambassador World Cup this year, the
incentives were not there for me, right?
And and obviously I've got to do this as
a job. You know, I love bug bounty
hunting and and I and sure I try to do
things for fun sometimes, but um as big
of a commitment as the Ambassador World
Cup is, it has to be a good opportunity
for me as a bug bounty hunter, right, as
well. And I just feel like the the dupe
um possibility going up and the, you
know, um negligible increase of bounties
or maybe not even an increase of
bounties
>> and and not really new scope either.
Yeah.
>> And not really new scope, right? It sort
of it sort of said I looked at that
opportunity and I was like I'm an H1
ambassador but like I I can't do that,
you know? Like
>> I do think it's different for you where
you already get to go to events though.
I think the real draw here for many
hackers was like the fact that the top
four went to a new event. So like while
Diego was already at those, he lots of
his teammates probably had never been to
a live event, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. J, what's your take on that?
>> Yeah, that's right. I think that um this
competition is meant to be for newcomers
or at least that was that was what um
Hikawan was was claiming at the
beginning. of course like uh having a
competition like like a team competition
uh is something that a lot of people and
especially Spanish people takes like
very serious and I think that's one of
the reasons why we we are like
performing really good because um it's
true that there is like there's not like
too many incentives for like spending
time in in in this competition because
as you said bounties might be the same
you have like no bonuses you have a high
risk of getting a duplicate because
there is a lot of people hunting at the
same applications. Um but for us is more
like um you know during all the year we
are always hunting alone most of the
times and we use this competition like
to get together. Um we don't really care
about bounties because in the end apart
from the this competition we are still
doing our our bounties. Some people have
their own job. So they don't care much
about the bounties in the competition
but of spending some time with the rest
of the team collaborating and also in
the end we are also getting a lot of
bugs and and and a lot of money as well.
So so I think that we are having that
perspective but I agree that is like
really demotivating to like not have for
example like a final reward for the
winners or like having bonuses for for
for those findings. So I I totally
understand the people that gets like
>> tired of of of this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean I I I think your
approach on it is is really solid and I
think that um like especially for
countries that have a lot of national
national pride in the competition space,
right? Like that makes a lot of sense
and and it's funny coming from an
American, right? Like at least we have
national pride, but we also have that
piece of individualism, right? Where
it's like, okay, well, if this doesn't
make sense for me, then I'm not going to
do it, you know? And um and so yeah, I
think there's there's a dichconomy
there, but I would definitely like to
see, you know, hacker one or or anybody
else who puts on, you know, something
similar. Um you know, we need live
hacking event like incentives here and
we need um you know, some sort of
duplicate shield, right? Whether you're
you you're segregating the teams out in
to different targets, right? Okay, you
know, these teams go to this target,
this team's go to this target, or you're
providing a dupe window um and some
asurances of like minimum bounty uh per
per team, right? Like so, for example,
if there's if there's a high that's
found, right? And it's found by 60
people, you know, and it's and it's a
and it's a you know, six grand high,
that's going to feel really bad, right?
you know, like um and and so I think
there needs to be some shield there
where it's like, okay, you know, your
team for every high you get, your team
will get at least $2,000 or $1,000 or
something like that, and then you can
split it across the team however you
will, but um there definitely needs to
be some better incentives there.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I agree with that.
>> Yeah. Um either way, congratulations,
man. It's a crazy competition. Um
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Yeah. I mean, Reza, like what else do we
want to say about about Diego, man? I
mean, he's a security researcher at
Expo, right? That's a big piece. Um, so,
uh, that's one of the reasons we wanted
to bring you on is because not only are
you performing at the top level in the
bug bounty competitions, but also you're
on the forefront of this AI, um, wave
that's happening. Um, so,
>> yeah, actually, just as like a very
small thing in that transition, I think
it makes sense to talk about at this
point. How did Expo reach out to you?
Like, did they find you off the
leaderboards? Was there like a onederee,
you know, separation of connection you
had? Like I'm just curious because I do
think a lot of our listeners will be
eventually
utilized in some way by hackbot
companies or they'll be using hack bots
themselves or they'll be using being um
wrapped up in like AI safety companies
or they'll be use AI safety tools like
I'm really curious how that initial
connection happened in case it's like
applicable to others.
>> Yeah. Uh so in this case I joined like
one year ago when the like the the team
the security team was was getting built
and in this case um the Neiman sec this
guy from Argentina Joel reached out to
me we are friends we have been
collaborating in previous events so he
know how how it works and I know how how
he works. Uh so he reached out to me
like hey I have like a really good
opportunity but that time I I was uh I
recently joined uh Xbox like in
Microsoft because I was part of
>> You did not. You went from Xbox to Xbow.
You changed one letter.
>> Yeah. So I was part of
>> I accidentally type Xbox every time I'm
trying to type expo. I do that every
time.
>> Yeah. I was part of uh the offensive
security at Activision Lethal King but
then we got bought by by Microsoft. So,
I moved to the Xbox gaming security team
and like once I was like a couple months
there, I I I got this offer from from
Expo and of course I decided to join.
Like the idea was amazing. The team is
insane. Uh probably one of the best
teams I ever seen. Uh not only in the
security part, but the people from
engineering, from AI is is crazy. So, so
I thought that it was like a unique
opportunity to join that even though it
was a risk to me like in the beginning,
but
>> I had to try of course.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. Well, I I'm I'm
glad you did because, you know, I think
like you said, they have a dream team
and you're a piece of that, right?
They've got the the AI dream team,
they've got really great management and
then they've got, you know, the the top
tier security researchers. So, that's
why I'm really I'm hopeful for it. And I
guess you know Reszo and I were kind of
discussing before this episode like um
we
we are we are fans of AI related stuff
you know for sure and um I'm definitely
rooting for Expo. there is a little bit
of skepticism obviously that that we're
bringing into this episode, right? And I
think a lot of
>> and in one part it's because I think we
want to represent that user base like
when I like whenever I quote tweeted
your all's findings, you know, there's
just like dozens of comments that are
like half are NA and informationational
and dupes, you know, and other people
are like it's all VDPs, right? And so I
think
>> I'm personally not that skeptical. I
think that Expo's product is probably
great, like probably fantastic just
because I've seen a lot of hack bots and
I know that you all are kind of like
leading the space, but I think we we
almost have to be skeptical because on
behalf of our listeners and because it
does affect our job outlook performance
stuff, too. So,
>> yeah. So, so I mean with with that,
Diego, what what I what I want to say
here is I want to give a little
disclaimer like we're rooting for you
guys. We're rooting for Expo, but we
also have to, you know, try to ask some
difficult questions on this podcast,
right? and to represent the listeners
and also to, you know, solve our own our
own thoughts on um on where Expo's at.
Um but yeah, the results have been
promising. I'm not going to lie, dude.
Um so, let's let's before we jump into
all of the expo pieces, all the
questions we've got, let's go ahead and
have you do the cloud test XXE um that
you guys released about uh for Expo. go
ahead and talk about that and uh show
what kind of uh technical prowess the um
the expo software has.
>> Okay.
Um yeah, so I don't know if you want to
like uh go through
>> I'll share my screen here. Hold on.
>> If anyone is living completely under a
rock expo is an autonomous pin testing
company and they have an account on
Hacker One that finds vulnerabilities.
Just to lay the the really the lowest
level of groundwork there. Thanks for
that. Thanks for that. Um, yeah. So, how
did you want to do this? Uh, Diego, did
you want to go straight through the
write up first or did you want to um
>> Yeah, we can go through the through the
right uh write up. Yeah. And then maybe
show the tray so that people can see how
it works.
>> Perfect.
>> Okay. So, yeah. So, this finding was
basically an XXC in akami cloud test.
Um, this is something that we originally
found in an asset from a hack one
program. So they were using this product
and um we we found this back. How how
expo works uh right now is you just
provide a URL, you provide like the
attack types that you want to test and
then you just wait for findings. Okay.
So of course there are more pieces
there. You can provide credentials, you
can provide um documentation if you
want. But of course in in in back bounty
usually um and in in this kind of
automations usually what you provide is
just a URL and you just let it uh find
bugs for you.
>> Do you do you ever just like paste in
the the program policy in case there's
some nuance there that you that it
should care about?
>> Do you ever just like throw that in into
the context?
>> Yeah. So we we we have like an
infrastructure where we monitor all the
domains that that are allowed by the
company. So whenever we start like um
like a test uh this uh infrastructure
checks the scope from that program and
for example if we have a URL that is out
of a scope or even though if doing the
trace like doing the interaction with XO
with a system it's it turns out that it
finds that asset which is out of scope
it won't test that. So it's like uh we
have some proxy rules that so every
traffic that goes to an asset that is
out of scope it it will get uh it will
will get blocked. So that we have some
some some word rates for that. Of
course, you know, this is automation.
This is an AI. We have some some issues
sometimes and that's why we are
constantly improving that so that we can
we can be sure that uh companies and
customers are safe and we are only
testing what is supposed to be tested.
>> Yeah. So so yeah. So in this case we we
just got like an asset from from a
customer um and in one of those
iterations XO decided to test for um
file rate vulnerabilities uh in this
case for XXE. We have like some attack
types uh like file read that includes
XXE pass reversal um and another kind of
um attack types. In this case it decided
to try to to try XXE. So we have to keep
in mind that the objective during this
trace like during this uh um uh
experiment uh is to find xx. Okay. Uh
this is something that has been uh
decided by like a higher coordinator
into the into the tool. Maybe we can
then um later talk about how it works
entirely. But in this case we are
testing this endpoint um this asset with
this specific attack type. So, so yeah,
it just do like a a human will do like
access to the site. See what it happens.
It gets like a redirect to uh um an
endpoint that is conferto and then it
starts to to try some some xxc uh
payloads. So yeah, we can this is like
how how the site looks and then um
during one of those iterations there are
some hallucinations during the process
but it finds an endpoint uh so endpoint
which is the repository service and of
course when you have these kind of
endpoints what you have to try is is an
XSC. It goes ahead, it tries the XSC and
then uh after trying a few payloads, it
gets an error which of course is giving
some evidence that some kind of XML
parsing is is is happening uh behind the
scenes.
>> When it says when it says it discovered
it, does it likely mean in the
JavaScript
>> in this case? Uh I think that it was a
really we can wink a check in the trace
but I think that this end point like
appear out of the blue like you know it
was trying to search it's it's funny
because in this trace it was trying to
search for a specific CVE which was like
an hallucination
uh because this this CV was not related
to this product and from that point it
managed to get this this uh endpoint. So
I guess that it has this information
probably in the in the training that
data that it has. That makes sense. We
we we saw that um some of the bugs that
we are going to disclose in in the in
the next couple next weeks. We saw that
uh um expo has a lot of information in
training data like about endpoints about
parameters and it you do like a lot of
weird combination with with those as
well. So so yeah we found that from from
from that I guess.
Um so yeah so then it starts trying some
sexy C payloads and if you go below you
will see that uh it fails. So then it
decides to try with inband outbound and
error based payloads. So again it tries
again to to get more information from a
wdl file that it founds with some
documentation and then tries a couple
more payloads. And then finally if you
go uh below
uh I don't want you to to bore you with
that. it tries a payload that it gets
like an interact uh into our interact uh
um system. So we have basically have
this integrated into expo. So we monitor
every request that that um is is
performed by by by expo using this um
filtration server. So we got a call back
and at that point we can confirm that
the XSC was working. But of course the
objective of the of this um of this tool
of expo is to um make sure that the the
vulnerability is real. So we we do not
like flag a bug until we have a clear
evidence that this works. So for that we
have some sort of validators. I don't
want to give a spoiler because one of
our teammates is going to be uh doing a
um a talk in in Black Hat in in a couple
weeks. But basically we have some system
um with a lot of validations that make
sure that um the finding is is not going
to be confirmed until we get a real
evidence in this case until we get some
file extracted from from the server. So
uh so then yeah if you go below is it it
finally uh crafts a payload um uh that
works. So if you go a little bit up, it
should be um Yeah, we have Yeah, a
little bit more up.
>> Yeah, there. So that's the the the the
payload. So basically, it creates a DTD
file pointing to um to a file that
doesn't exist to force the error base
and then uh it points to the etc
password. So it will basically uh do an
error based xxe and then in the other in
the other request you just point to the
ddd file. It's just a normal xe and you
get finally the in the in the the error
you get the the response from the file.
>> So when you get password in slack do you
just freak out? I mean like like is is
your face as a bug body hunter just like
your jaw on the floor like I don't know
what's the reaction there?
>> Yeah. So, so we we we really are used uh
to that right now like at the beginning
it was like oh an anxe an RC you know uh
but now every day we have like these
kind of findings uh we have a Slack
channel where we got uh we get all these
uh notifications and we we get like the
type of bug that we that Exo found and
and we go there and check that if is a
true positive or not. Of course, we have
this kind of validators that make sure
that that is always a a true positive,
but you know the we are still fixing
some issues because sometimes the AI
manage to cheat this kind of validators
is something that is also used to uh so
so we are constantly improving that. Uh
but for some for some uh attack types
and vulnerability types we have zero
false positives like right now we we
don't have any false positives you know.
>> Wow that's amazing. So, so looking at
this exploit, I mean this required out
of banan interaction, right? Which you
guys have implemented with uh interact
it seems like um so many questions about
that. One, you know, in this scenario,
it seems like the AI can host a DTD file
>> um and then you know it can know where
it's hosted and then point stuff to it.
So that's something that the AI is
capable of doing autonomously.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So, so we have um
we have an attack on machine basically
with a hosting service and then we have
this uh excfiltration server and yeah we
have like a lot of components that is
data provided to the to the AI whenever
it start to to to like start finding
bugs in an application. So with all that
information in the prompts and how to
use these tools and how to host a file
and how to use the interact server with
all this information uh expo can start
running and interact with all these
pieces.
>> Dude that's crazy. So, so
architecturally, I mean, as much as you
can, uh, you know, talking about expose
architecture because I know it's it's
um, you know, proprietary, but um, like
how how does this work with out of band
stuff? Like does the AI just kind of
say, "All right, I yeeded a request out
there. I threw a request out there. Now
I'm going to wait and see, you know, and
like and then how does the the data get,
you know, pushed back into the prompt or
uh that that's fed to the actual agent
that's doing the, you know, hands on the
keyboard hacking versus like the the
coordinator or conductor or whatever.
>> Yeah. So in this case, whenever we start
like a new assessment and let's say an
assessment is when you want to scan a
URL, um we we have like a unique
interactive stage server for for that
specific asset.
Um and we have also like a specific
attack machine where we where we can
host all the files that we want to use
uh for that specific assessment. Um so
so yeah whenever we want to try for
example for XXCE we can use those tools
and we will have like some sort of
system that is monitoring those
requests. So whenever we get a request
from from let's say from a from an XC
payload uh automatically in the next
iteration we'll have that into the
prompt like hey I just got like this
call back from from the server. So it's
probably uh that your previous payload
has worked. So, so we have some ways to
track from which um uh from which
iteration this payload comes comes from
because of course we know that some
payloads might not work like uh at that
same moment and maybe you get the call
back in 5 minutes. So we have a system
to kind of what I was thinking is like
is like you know maybe you know you send
it and then 5 minutes later some backend
job you know uh it gets it and then so
does it just pick up right where it left
off when it issued that request and you
load up all the context and then you say
and now you've got a hit so now do
something with that you know uh does do
you give all that information to the AI
as well as information about like oh you
know there's this amount of time between
when you sent the request and when the
hit occurred
>> yeah so we a way whenever so whenever we
we we perform these requests we have a
way to track that and of course the AI
is also like clever uh to follow like
where this this request might come from
you know so also we we help that uh with
for example you you want to perform like
you want to test an xxe payload we can
maybe just add like a slash xxe1 so you
can track where this uh callback comes
from so that kind of hints are are like
tips that we provide in the prompt so
that the the AI knows how to work and
how to identify those requests.
>> Also, also Justin, there's also like a
natural delay here just from the fact
that you know these models don't output
tokens instantly. Like if you think
about it as it's writing the response
and getting to the next trace and doing
the next step, especially if they're
using reasoning models under the hood,
it's going to naturally take like, you
know, 30 seconds to a minute between
things. So, I bet a lot of times they
kind of get it for free. Or if it's if
it's not on the first next step in the
trace, it might be on the the one after
that because then it's been five minutes
or whatever. You know,
>> it seems to me like there needs to be
like a decision tree of sorts that
happens here, right? Like like you know,
okay, the AI tries um you for an out-
ofband call, right? And then, you know,
this decision tree path says, okay,
well, the out of-band call didn't come
back, so I'm going to keep iterating.
And then you know if you do get some
call back at some point now we've got
this path over here where it's like okay
I got the call back you know but but
>> that's a good question that's a good
question does it does it branch or is it
always like singular in the way that it
obviously the orchestrator can spin off
multiple instances but for a single
instance does it branch at all or does
it just keep going in like a single
line?
>> Yeah. So yeah, so uh that's right. You
have we have like some sort of uh like
coordinator that um that can have like
multiple what we call solvers. The
solvers is like a unique pentester that
we that has an objective and it goes to
that. So um let's say that when we are
doing um when we are running XO against
an application and we um and we run that
the coordinator do like some sort of
discovery process get some endpoints and
then start like popping up solvers with
different objectives. So this one might
try this endpoint with this attack type.
This other might try xxe with this
endpoint. So then those are unique.
Okay. So you have all the context like
you have some um limited uh iterations
for that uh solver and you have all the
context from what that solver is doing
and that solver has like a very unique
objective like you want to try xxs in
this endpoint and until it doesn't find
an xss it will like consume all the
iterations and then it will stop with
the final or with like hey here I
couldn't find anything and then it
continues so the coordinator has like
all the information about what the other
solvers are trying. But then when once a
solver starts that's unique like you you
will be only trying that until you run
out of iterations.
>> Wow that's that's amazing dude. That
sounds like a really cool architecture
and and so I guess you know when you
said you have these different you know
solvers these different pentesters right
it reminded me of the trace right so if
at the end of which is one of the
coolest parts about this blog post by
the way like please always continue to
include these traces because that is
really cool to see um so for any of you
any of you guys that aren't on on
YouTube or haven't read the write up if
you scroll down to the bottom of this
cloud test xxe writeup that was done by
expo um there is a a little box at the
bottom that shows the chain of thought
for the AI that is uh you know attacking
this specific endpoint and how it
uncovered this vulnerability and it's
amazing and one of the ones that I saw
down here um I'm trying to see if I can
find where it is but I think it was
pentester 28. Yeah, look at this right
here. This one says pentester 28 check
read file and then you know it's trying
for an LFI of sorts or LFD. Um so how
many of these things are you spinning up
to attack you know a given a given
target or a given asset that you've been
given by uh a target?
>> Yeah so it really depends you know um we
know that right now we can perform
better with some specific type of
issues. Um so it really depends on on
what we like to look for. If let's say
that we want to focus on server side
because 4G uh then we will run like a
specific number of of pentesters for
that specific task you know so we have
like different modes of running u this
this kind of uh experiments that we call
and it really depends like that's
something that we can configure
ourselves. So whenever we want to run
some experiments and scan some URLs, we
define how many uh ancestors or solvers
we want to run, how many iterations and
what kind of attack types we want to
focus on. So So yeah.
>> Wow. That's
>> Are you are you all personally able to
spin them up? Like for example, like
let's say you're doing bug bounty on the
clock and so you're you know you're
intentionally testing Expo. Do you ever
use it for like um like accomplishing a
single task? Like that's one thing I've
often thought about is like, you know, a
lot of these systems are built to
basically be like an abstract hacker,
like go find bugs on this blackbox
domain. But then the other use case is
like a it's like almost like a um a
precision needle. It's like, hey, I'm
looking at this specific request and I
think there might be excess in this
parameter test for only that, you know,
are you able to kind of hand it
something very specific like that?
>> Yeah. So we have like two different
modes. Um one of them is like you just
get um a URL and you want to try SSRF
for example. So you will just do like
everything in that single uh solver and
then we have like the coordinator way
that I was talking before where the
coordinator decides what what endpoints
want to try and so let's say that we
have some some discovery phase where we
start getting uh endpoints we start
filling forms we start like mapping the
application and then the coordinator
decides like okay this specific feature
I want to try that with uh SSRF so it
provides all the context on how to get
into there, what kind of authentication
is it requires in case like he had to
register or like um authenticate into
the application and then just like all
the information that it needs to try
that specific type of bug in that
specific endpoint. So that's how it
works and and so we have like um an
lower amount of iterations for those u
solvers that are like very specific. Uh
so that's how it works. It's like
spinning a lot of different solvers to
try every single endpoint from from the
application and that's something that we
are improving right now like making sure
that we cover all the endpoints and all
the features from from an application
and of course you can set some
boundaries as well like if you don't
want to test something you can block
that in in in in the tool. So we have
some specific part into in our UI where
you can define what kind of ends you
don't want to hit or what feature you
want to avoid testing just in case.
Yeah, there is any restriction. So,
>> this is I was out on a run this morning
and I was listening to a podcast on AI
related stuff and one of the things that
they've said on this podcast and and you
know, Joseph, you probably know more
about this than I do was how important
data labeling is for some of this stuff
and and I'm wondering, you know, uh I if
Expo has has utilized that at all. like
how much how much training and I know
we've got some you know one of the
things you said before we came on the
pod was like we can't disclose what
models we're using you know and what
other stuff like that but I I'm
wondering you know what that training
process looks like you know are are you
having seasoned pentesters go through
and you know label what kind of
endpoints should be interesting what and
why they're interesting and help the AI
do that or are you mostly relying on the
AI's sort of brain of sorts right to to
determine whether okay you know maybe I
shouldn't trying LFI on this CSS file,
you know, sort of thing, right?
>> Do you mean for fine-tuning, Justin?
>> Yeah. Yeah, for fine-tuning or just for
like um Yeah. I mean, I guess more so
for fine-tuning.
>> My guess is that they don't use fine
tuning. I don't know if Diego can tell
us, but I'm definitely curious if he's
able to.
>> Yeah, I cannot tell that. But
>> try.
>> Yeah. No. So, so to answer to Justin
question, basically we have some sort of
um intelligence behind the product where
we know what to focus. So, of course, if
you have like a JS file, you don't want
to probably test for SSRF unless you
have some sort of parameters included.
So, that kind of logic is included into
the tool. So we will only use JS files
to read them to go through that and
understand how the application work but
not to test them. So that that sort of
logic is is included of course uh from
our experience into the product. So, so
>> is that from the prompting perspective
like you guys have built prompts to
direct it you know towards okay you know
use JS files like this use you know
dynamic endpoints like this or
>> it's not part of the prompt is part of
the how the the tool is is built
>> okay
>> how the coordinator works and all the
stuff
>> okay so there's some hard logic behind
expo where it's like okay this is a JS
file you know and you know that's
interesting that's kind of how I
architected my recon system back in the
day was was you know I would ingest a
bunch data, I would drop it into like a
queue, right? And then the queue would
understand what kind of data this is.
Okay, this is a JS file. So now I throw
this off to a different um you know sort
of queue where it's like, okay, we're
going to parse the JS files and try to
extract endpoints. We're going to you
know um try to iterate on the JS files
to find older versions. You know, we
know these are all of the cues that JS
files go into. And then and then you
kind of have uh you know, whatever
scripts you're using to process those JS
files. And I imagine this is sort of a
similar architecture. Yeah, exactly. So,
it's like a way to help the AI to not uh
test things that you shouldn't shouldn't
test like you know, of course, you don't
want to test like a PNG file or for or
XSS probably. So, so that kind of things
is um and we saw that doing like we saw
the AI doing that kind of stuff in in in
the past.
>> Uh so that that's like getting some help
to the AI to avoid doing doing uh that
kind of stuff. Listen, you got to check,
you know, sometimes you just got to
check. It might it might happen, you
know.
>> I mean, and and it happened actually the
other day. Um, and hopefully we can
disclose this soon, but we found um a
local file inclusion uh where there was
some sort of system that gets uh an
image and you can decode bite by bite.
So, you can just generate like a a a PNG
like an image file with the content of a
file of the system file and you can then
decode it. So, we're going to share
something related uh fully soon. That's
amazing. That's crazy.
>> And that that's one of the cases where
you have like a PNG file with some sort
of parameters that we are doing some
some stuff behind the scenes and
actually found a local fine inclusion.
So, yeah.
>> Yeah. Justin, do you mind if I ask about
like kind of um false positive rates and
that sort of thing real quick?
>> Okay. Well, let's let's let's stay
focused on this specific right because I
I'm very much wanting to dive deep into
Expo and how it works and all of that
sort of thing, but um let's let's get
through this one and then we'll we'll go
through that list. So, put it in the doc
for now. I actually was about to just
about to ask about harnesses. So, yeah.
Uh yeah. Well, I'm I'm not going to I
we'll get through this write up and then
we'll go back to, you know, expo how
it's actually working. Um all right. So
going back to the uh the write up a
little bit here. It seems like from this
trace what's happening here Diego is it
is generating Python code right and then
it's using that to explore the
application and it's getting this sort
of response back that it then parses and
makes you know deductions about about
the app. Is that the typical flow that
you guys use you know for for this sort
of um you know like testing for XXE or
is it you know obviously individual for
various types like XSS or you know DOM
based stuff?
>> Yeah. So basically uh for every attack
type that we have we have some sort of
reasoning. So basically it analyzes what
the application is returning from the
previous command and is deciding what to
try next. So that's basically how it
works. Always you have you need to keep
in mind that we always have an objective
that has been defined when this pentest
has started. In this case we were tasked
with with finding like a file read
vulnerability. Um so so you you have to
take that in mind. Uh and then just the
AI decides what try next.
>> Yeah. So I can see up at the top here
it's like okay looking for potential
file inclusion vulnerabilities. we see
later down, you know, it's trying for
all of these sort of known payloads. Um,
and then, you know, this is where it
really gets interesting for me, right?
Right here, um, on the screen. So, I'll
read a little a little snippet from it.
The, um, you know, it's it it's notes a
piece of the response that says, XML NS
Xelon um, and it knows that that's an
XSLT processor. So, it starts thinking
XXE. That's a reasonable deduction,
right? Um,
and you know, it says, okay, the problem
states the vulnerability is at this
spot, right? You know, and and so I
guess from what you've told me so far
that this is a the way you're phrasing
this to the solver, right? Um, you're
saying, hey, there is a vulnerability at
this specific endpoint and you're you're
telling it to try to go solve it, right?
Versus like there might be a
vulnerability here. Did you guys, you
know, try around with both of those? One
of the most difficult problems for a
hacker is to know when to stop
something's not vulnerable or something
is vulnerable. So how do you how do you
solve that problem with the AI?
>> Yeah. So in this case we are not like uh
we are not telling uh the eye like
there's a specific issue. We are just
asking to find that uh because we don't
want like to um you know uh we want to
give freedom to the AI. So we may give
like initial objective but then if the
decides to go through and try another
thing related to that objective that has
been specified it can do that as well.
>> Why does why does it say the problem
states the vulnerability is at if it's
not in the prompt.
>> Yeah. So uh this this specific uh
pentester comes from the high level
coordinator. So probably at one point
the coordinator has found like has
decided to try for this specific uh file
inclusion vulnerabilities and then it
started as a solver uh to try to achieve
that and then inside that um it will try
different options like xxe or path
traversal or whatever because the
objective that we have is to extract one
file from the server like the etc
password file.
Yeah, I think I think what Justin's
asking is that the the wording there is
very strongly worded like it says the
vulnerability is at which is like it it
implies that the prompt says something
along the lines of there is a
vulnerability at URL rather than there
might be a vulnerability or look for
vulnerabilities at URL. Like it's pretty
weird phrasing from the LLM to say
because I know the vulnerability is at
this. It almost it almost reads as if
you fed it that there's a vulnerability
there which I know you told us you all
don't do. So I think that's why we're
kind of like pressing into this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. In this case I need to make
sure until unless they have done some
changes. I would say that we are not
like um giving that information to the
to the to the coordinator like we are
asking to find but we are not like
saying hey here is a 100%. So, right
though, Justin,
>> to kind of like just tell it there is
one. And since you're going to cut it
off after so many cycles anyways, it
might be gaslighting it a little bit,
but in some ways it would probably make
it more persistent, right? Like if
you're working on a CTF and you know
there is a vulnerability and you're
giving it to a model, you would want to
say, "I know there's a flag here." You
know what I mean? Yeah.
>> That kind of confidence kind of
interesting.
>> Maybe that's the coordinator doing that,
right, Diego?
>> Yeah. Exactly. So, so that that's the
difference between like doing an
assessment and trying to solve a CTF,
you know. Um, in this case, if you want
to solve a CTF, of course, you need to
make sure that the the coordinator knows
that there is a indeed there is an
aability and it has to find one. And in
this case if we if we uh say that
there's a vulnerability in this this
specific endpoint uh the solver might
try like again and again and again and
we will end up consuming a lot of
iterations without finding anything. So
we always give freedom to the AI to stop
whenever it thinks that uh it cannot
finds anything. So in for example in
this case if it started finding trying
to find local find inclusion and then
ends up like okay I've wast like a lot
of iterations and I cannot find anything
it will stop and then it will continue
with another part of the application or
with a different endpoint or whatever.
>> That makes sense. So so you're giving a
little bit of freedom to the AI here.
That's that's interesting. And we're
also seeing a little bit of tactics
being implemented from the um
coordinator saying okay you know there
the problem states there is a
vulnerability here right so maybe it's
saying to the thing you know there's a
vulnerability here go test it go find it
right um it could be a strategy and then
like you said before and this was
something that read really weird
whenever we whenever we um were reading
this write up that we wanted to talk to
you about but luckily you addressed
earlier on which is I I'll read this for
the people that are on audio a quick
search reveals a known XXE and redacted
cloud test and then lists a bogus CV
number. Uh this CV describes an XXE
vulnerability in the the conerto uh
service REST repository service
endpoint. Specifically, when posting XML
data with an external entity, the
affected versions are this uh this is
our current build number. Um so it
doesn't really match up. However,
redacted cloud test became a cloud test.
So this is highly relevant which is
which is interesting, right? Um, so I
I'm trying to figure out exactly what's
happening here. Maybe there's a bit of
hallucination. Maybe there isn't. Um, I
I was trying to do research on this
repository service URL before this
episode and it seems to have just yked
it out of, you know, nowhere, right?
Like where did this even come from? So,
I'm wondering, you know, what your take
is on this because, uh, on one hand, we
could say, whoa, it's AI magic, you
know, uh, and how did it know, you know,
but for for us that are hackers, you
know, we kind of wanted a a more
concrete answer to where this this URL
came from. Um, and I'm I'm curious to
hear your thoughts on that.
>> Yeah, so that's what I was mentioning
before. It seems that this endpoint
comes like from the training data set.
uh because that CVE is not even part of
like an accommodation
from the AI. So it might be relating
some common like some um known endpoint
with uh with with a C CV that doesn't
make sense. Uh so yeah that's a
completely hallucination and it's funny
because the other day I was talking with
my boss like hey thanks to this specific
hallucination we managed to test this
endpoint like otherwise and if you see
that endpoint is not the right one you
know the final one is the same without
the rest uh part. So of course it
managed to find like that endpoint which
is probably part of the training data
set. If you go back like below to the to
the very end, you will see that the
vulnerable one is without the rest. So
after trying and and doing yeah after
trying and doing some some attempts, it
realizes that that endpoint doesn't
exist because it returning a 404 and
then it finds the other one. It goes
back to the WSDL. It reads that and it
gets the right endpoint from that.
>> Dude, that's crazy. I didn't pick up on
that the first read. Yeah. Look at this
right here. 404. Yeah. Wow. Okay. That's
that's whack. Um but it's just odd to
me. I mean like I I hate to keep pushing
the point, but like it's odd to me that
shrouded in all of this um
hallucination, right? You know, it's
hallucinating about the CVE. It it's
hallucinating about these version
numbers a little bit. It it it seems to
me like it's hallucinating about this
this line. However, redacted cloud test
became a cloud test. So, this is highly
relevant. I tried to look into like old
CVS like what what was the product
before it became Alchemy Cloud Test like
did this get acquired what did it get
renamed what happened and I couldn't
find anything related to that.
>> I I will say Justin and there's kind of
two points to bring up about this. One
is that um at the scale of expose
running these, they're probably not
using like really large models and these
types of hallucinations or le at least
not the very, you know, state-of-the-art
models because it would just be so
expensive to run on like Claude Opus 4
or something.
>> And so these types of hallucinations are
pretty common in in like the
non-state-the-art models. And then the
other thing,
>> where does it get that end point though,
dude? Like shrouded in that whole Well,
hold on. In that whole bit of
hallucination, right? Yes, so many
things hallucinated. The endpoint is the
thing that isn't hallucinated,
>> right? But that makes sense, right? Like
if if you imagine in the training data,
it's seen that endpoint multiple times
like those three tokens in
consecutiveness. And further up in its
trace, it's also been finding like it
actually found a real endpoint at
Concerto Services, repository service.
It just now hallucinated and added in
rest probably because there was, you
know, a lot of um training data where it
services rest, right? Because it's, you
know, it's still a token completion
engine. And so anyways, the other thing
I was going to tell you is that like
reasoning traces are actually often
wrong with a lot of hallucinations. This
is something that's been studied pretty
heavily with like the deepseek models.
So the the deepseek models and other
reasoning models, Justin, will be used
to like solve math and physics problems.
And when you look at the reasoning
trace, it's all wrong. Like the like the
the intermediate steps are all wrong,
but the final answer will be correct,
right? And that's one thing that's
interesting about bug bounty is it's
like and at the scale of of hackbots
right now if you're running a thousand
of them it's like it doesn't matter if
the majority hallucinate or even if like
their logic's wrong as long as they find
a real vulnerability at the end that's
actually what matters to the customer.
>> Yeah. I mean that makes total sense. I'm
sorry Diego. I know I'm just de debating
here with Joseph, but um it, you know,
I'm I'm trying to think about how this
could possibly be happening. And the
only thing that I can think of is that
this the the model that that has this,
you know, uh because this is not, you
know, this this endpoint is not
something that you just like it's not
really even guessable, right? Like if it
was like API user, you know, whatever
that
>> Oh, it's got to be in the training data.
You're right. It's in the training data.
The source code for this app is in the
training data or they've got like uh you
know a a documentation logs. Exactly. Or
>> there's a zero day and somehow it has
access to that zero day as a part of its
training base. Right. So somewhere
buried in in Reddit somewhere buried in
you know the dark web or whatever and
that somehow made its way into this
model's training data there is a
reference to this endpoint. Do do you
have any theories about that Diego?
>> I don't know. Like we we were thinking
that it's probably part of the training
data. Um and we thought that we are like
really sure that it's part of the
training data, but we we cannot know
like we don't know.
>> That's interesting.
>> So Justin, I I I was going down a
similar path when you were reading this
and looking at it. Let me let me share
my screen real quick because I think
that it might um convince you otherwise.
And I think this is like really
important even for the listeners just
about how like you know next token
completion works.
>> So so I was searching for services
repository service. I was searching for
other things before this and it was all
just pointing back to the expo write up
right it's like all things that like
reference the write up or that find
vulnerabilities like nuclei or whatever.
>> But then when I finally did this search
services repository service
>> it got 2k hits. So like there are 2,000
projects that have like services
repository service services repository
service right as as a as a chain of
tokens that exist across lots of apps
like literally 2,000 places right and so
the the these tokens services repository
service like are side by side very very
many times in the training set
especially around like code and projects
and like you know even XML based stuff.
So, I don't think that it is like really
that much of a leap at all for it to um
>> interesting have have like put those two
tokens together specifically.
>> My faith is weak, you know, my faith is
weak in the AI the our AI overlords like
forgive forgive my unbelief, you know.
Um but yeah, no, that makes sense. And
when you look at the logic, um you
kicked me off the screen. Sorry, you can
screen. You're good. I I'll I'll share
it again. It it is interesting because
it does mention the WSDL, right? Like
you said, Diego, right? So, you know,
maybe this WSDL somehow ended up in the
trainer set, the training set, or you
know, maybe through the flows, right,
with the with the um um I I keep on
forgetting what's the the parent called,
the conductor, the
>> Oh, the the coordinator.
>> The coordinator.
>> So, you know, maybe some some up there
with the coordinator, right? You know,
is passing this down because it parsed a
WS SDL later on, you know, or earlier on
in the assessment and it's like, oh, I
saw some reference to this. So, I guess
there's a lot of things going on there,
but um that's that's the kind of stuff
that's really amazing to me, man, about
about these things. And and Joseph, I
didn't know that piece about how all of
the inferences are wrong, but somehow
the result is right.
>> Yeah, this actually this is actually a
big mystery, and it makes um researchers
wonder if like the real reasoning is
occurring in the model at inference time
as it bounces between the different like
um I guess nodes is kind of a way to say
it. and that the reasoning trace is like
not true evidence of like the what what
what's actually occurring in the model
and it's it's an area of open research
that a lot of people have been
discussing because on these evals where
where these new models will score really
well on math and physics test when they
go and they look at the reasoning traces
they're often wrong or there's
hallucinations in them and so this is
like almost like it's a very similar
style of thing here.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I think that's that's
fascinating and I'm sorry to push a
little bit on it on it, Diego, but I I I
do think that that is a really cool part
of what you guys have found here. And I
imagine you your team is, you know,
anytime a valid vulnerability is found,
are you guys looking through the chain
of of thought for each of these
vulnerabilities and like understanding
exactly what the AI did right, what it
did wrong, where it got the information,
and how you can use that to improve the
prompting.
>> Yeah. So we always try to check those
but of course we have like thousand of
them like every day we have a lot of
hits we have to to check them and we we
cannot like validate all the different
traces also as we are running uh
multiple times against the same
applications sometimes we find like the
same XSS or the same XXE or the same rce
like from a different like with
different trace. So you you cannot
compare them. But yeah, we always try to
look for patterns so that we can improve
how the tool is working and and we see
that it's doing a lot of times the same
uh wrong thing. We try to uh change the
prompt and and modify that to to fix
that behavior.
>> Yeah. Speaking of that, I know you said
that you all have really great
validators, but sometimes they get
hacked by the models bypassing them to
get them straight into your all Slack.
You know, if if you're able to even just
ballpark it, like what is the false
positive rate? is are you know for ones
that actually get through to Slack is it
like 50% or is it like 10% like
obviously those are really big
differences because like if it if it
were something like 10% true positive
then like it's not really the AI model
that's finding it completely because you
all are you know ruling out 90% and
validating them or for the for the
attack types that are not being hacked
is it actually a lot closer to like
100%.
>> Yeah. So I don't have the numbers but it
really depends. For example, we know
that for some specific attack types we
have no false positives. So for example
uh the XSS which is which is a very
simple one we always run a headless
browser whenever we find like um
vulnerability. So whenever one of the
solvers find finds a vulnerability um we
have a a validator that checks the XSS
that has found and it validates that um
is popping up with a header browser an
alert or whatever it has found. So we
have some checks to verify that we don't
have false positives uh related to this.
But of course for other type of issues
like SSRF at the beginnings we have some
some issues because we like the the the
pentesters the solvers were trying to
use some external services to hit our uh
like our interact SH server. So we had
to fix that adding new rules to like
fixing the proxy fixing the DNS rules
that we have so that there's no way to
perform a direct request to this uh to
this interactive stage server from like
the different location but of course the
AI always comes with different uh
different sheets and different ways to
to hack that uh and that's that's one
one of the of the parts that we are
actually working on like improving the
the false positive
But right now we are in a pretty good
good state. I don't want to like give so
like too too much spoilers because in
Black Hat we are going to have one of
our teammates giving a full talk about
this. So I don't want to to
>> that's that's interesting that you're
saying that it's in a good state though.
I mean I trust your opinion on this
Diego. Like if you if you tell me it's
it's producing pretty good results you
know I believe you. Um I think you have
a good
>> it always depends on the window types
you know um things like open redirect
for example is super easy to to verify
we don't have any false positive there
but of course we have some some cases
where
>> like info disclosure I'm sure it thinks
that some keys are sensitive that aren't
and stuff like that right
>> yeah there's some type of issues that is
hard to detect nowadays and you don't
have like um ways to easily validate
them so so we are um we are like
limiting to the things that we can
detect without false positives. You
know, uh one of the the keys from from
Expo is that we don't want to um to
deliver a lot of false positive
positives to the to the to the
customers. So, of course, we might be
losing some good findings during the
way, but we don't want to like provide
hundred of false positives to the to the
customer. So we are prioritizing to to
at least at the beginning uh limit the
number of false positivities that we
have and during the way we are we are
improving that so that we don't miss
anything.
>> So that that's why the coordinator is
that what that was uh that that is why
uh this system and this infrastructure
is built so that we don't miss anything.
>> I I had another question about sort of
the the harness interface. Is it okay if
I pivot to that? Joseph, did you have
any follow-ups there?
>> No, that's good.
>> Okay. Um, you know, throughout the and I
I stopped sharing the screen now. I
think that's probably the last uh, you
know, question we'll do on the trace,
but in that trace, it it showed that
there was um, sometime it's generating
Python code and then it's running that
code to interact with the server.
Sometimes it's building raw HTTP
requests from from scratch, right? And
then it's, you know, putting them in a
file and then passing that file to some
some program. It seems that will, you
know, send it to the server. Um I I'm
curious about you know how much freedom
you give the AI to do these sort of
things uh and whether you found whether
one technique you know using having it
generate code having it generate raw
HTTP requests having it use tools to
modify an already present HTTP request
like set body or set query parameter
whatever are any of those more effective
than others? Yeah. So something that we
saw is that uh using Python scripts are
really really good. Uh we we so it's
also a way to something that we have in
the prompt is that um we want to be as
much efficient as possible. So we don't
want to uh like consume all the
iterations from from a solver just doing
like cool requests. So if you can just
create a Python splits that performs
five requests and try five different
payloads in the same iterations that is
much better of course. So we are always
trying to do that and that's why you can
see a lot of Python use in in our traces
because we are we are using that also we
saw that some of the models that we are
using are much better when when when
using Python than when using core or
other tools. So, so we are prioritizing
that.
>> Writing cookies and bearer tokens and
stuff in Python is pretty annoying
though. Uh, and also uses a lot of
tokens. Do you all have some way that
you kind of just like wrap it in O?
>> Sorry, what? Can you repeat that?
>> Do you have a way that it that the
Python script is just kind of like
wrapped in authentication or something
so that it like inherits or uses a
cookie jar or you know just does
something like that? because obviously
like models rewriting massive cookie
strings or like useless headers or
bearer tokens is like really annoying.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So we have um that's funny
because the authentication part is like
a different game, you know. Uh we we had
a lot of issues with that and it's
something uh it's also something that we
we had to improve a lot and we are
improving nowadays like dealing with
with authentication. So, so yeah, um
it's like a completely different game
and there's a lot of stuff behind that.
Um we always give some some advices to
the solver on how to deal with
authentication, how to deal with tokens.
Uh so whenever it's is playing around
with with request, uh it doesn't forget
about authentication. If it has like
previously authenticated with with an
account, it always has to remember that.
So we have some prompting behind that to
to do that as well. Yeah, even even with
generating the Python request, a lot of
times these WS will block you know
Python request certain user agents.
Yeah.
>> Right. So it's like I feel like you got
to hook the Python request library and
like you know override the user agent
and I feel like you've got to hook you
know like you said some cookie jar
related thing because yeah getting the
AI to manage all of that is got to be
really tricky. Um yeah. Yeah.
>> Wow. Very interesting. Um, all right.
Well, we uh we kind of went through a
lot of the the write up. I think this is
an hourong uh segment here, which is the
first, you know, like prove your prove
how your uh hacking skills are, but sets
a record in the the CTVB history, I
think. Um, so let's yeah, let's dive a
little bit deeper into into Expo and and
the architecture. You talked a lot about
the, you know, coordinator and then
you've got these various solvers
underneath. Are there more pieces to the
puzzle? How how have you guys
architected this thing?
>> Yeah, so basically we have some some
moving pieces. We have uh the attack
machine that I was mentioning this like
um like a completely isolated machine
that we use for every uh solver. So
whenever a new solver starts, we have an
attack machine that performs all the
actions and then uh it it it goes down.
Um and that that that attack machine
includes all the services that I was
mentioning like the collaborator and the
hosting service and and and all that
stuff. Um also we have um we have like
the report generating stuff. So whenever
we find something we have um like um
like another different agent that
performs the the like the report and
generates a report so that then we can
send it to the customer or to hacker one
and all that. And then we have like the
validation validation stuff. And yeah, I
think I'm not missing anything from
that. Uh let me remember. But I think
that's that's all. Um
>> yeah, we have also some some network
stuff going going as well like behind
the scenes so that we make sure that we
follow all the like the safe uh
safeguards we we are implementing and we
make sure that we don't go out of the
scope and all that. But that's like
different different
>> part. I I think that that makes sense
from an architectural perspective and
what we've studied you know just Joseph
and I talking as well is that that's
pretty much the way that you must um you
know build these larger scale systems
and and one of the difficulties that we
actually covered on a previous episode
of uh critical thinking is how do you
convey context from your your
coordinator you know down to your
solvers and stuff like that. Is that a
problem that you guys have addressed at
all or is that something you guys have
struggled with?
>> Yeah. So, so that's something that the
EI team could say better than me uh
because I don't know all the all the
things that are running behind but I
know that they have been dealing with
with context. So that uh every time that
we start like a new solver with with
a a specific objective or trying to look
for a specific attack type, we provide
all the previous context about
authentication. We provide sessions. We
provide a way to reach that endpoint so
that we make sure that uh we follow all
the steps to get into that into into
that same step.
>> Are you provided gadgets from other
threads or no? That's always something
that I thought would be really
interesting was if you saved off or
partial bugs.
>> No, we are just providing like the way
to reach that uh endpoint and all the
stuff. Yeah,
>> that makes sense, man. That must be nice
to have the the whole AI team, you know,
behind you being like, "Yeah, you guys
deal with that whole context."
>> That's actually a perfect transition. I
had that I had that exact question,
Diego. I've noticed in the companies
that I meet with, like the Hackbot
companies that I've met with or that I
talked to, that before I was there, if
they didn't have, this isn't true of
Ethiak, um, you know, which I'm an
adviser for because obviously it was
founded by Andre, who's like a very top
bug bounty hunter, but for the other
companies that don't have like bug
hunters, even if they had pentesters on
the team, it felt like their path or
their trajectory was not as impactbased
or not as practical as we are as bug
hunters, right? because we're like
impact or GTFO, right? It's like if
there's no impact, you don't get paid.
>> And so I'm just genuinely curious like
if not asking you to say anything bad
about the team, but whenever you joined
the team or maybe was Nemanc already
there.
>> Yeah. So maybe it's a question for him,
but I would be curious if you all ran
into that at all, right? Where there was
like some sort of disconnect where it's
like they have the hackbot looking for
like TLS version differences and you're
like, "No, those aren't going to fly."
Right? Like we need to actually look for
real bugs or something. like I didn't
know if there was any kind of friction
like that.
Yeah, that's something that that's also
why we created this kind of validators
like we don't um of course this is quite
different for for for for companies and
for c customers if you perform appenses
you want to deliver all the results and
you would like to include that as well
and we have another way to include that
information into our reports and then we
have the other way like a way to prove
that we are indeed getting a valid
finding like an XXE or an RC
uh and that's why we we have these sort
of validators and then for the rest of
vulnerabilities we have other ways to
detect that which we are still working
on and I think I cannot keep too many
details.
>> No, that's fine. I actually I don't know
if I recently tweeted or told a couple
people but I think that validation is
going to be one of the biggest kind of
subindustries in AI in the next few
years because there's so many domains
where you need really strong validation
of output.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, it's it's
interesting, man. And and there's
there's so many um so so many places
that I could take the conversation at
this point. My my my brain is exploding.
Um I I think one of the things that I'm
interested in just in general as a bug
bounty hunter is how Bug Bounty is such
a great platform for startups to go and
clearly we can see Expo utilizing Bug
Bounty as a way to um validate the the
product and also maybe even recuperate
some of the cost of operating.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Right. Um and and so I
know that there was a tweet that I'll
I'll put out um from your CEO
saying that currently it operates the um
you know the tool operates at a negative
you know amount right like the amount
it's earning from from bounties at a
loss. Thank you. um it you know
surpasses the amount uh that it it costs
to run it you know it it's it's running
negative but um I guess where do you see
that mostly being addressed in the
future via um you know increasing prices
the cost of compute going down uh the
tool becoming more efficient and finding
things better or how do you think that's
going to change and what timeline do you
have for that
>> yeah so so I think it's a mix of a
couple things but the main one is that
we all think that inference cost going
to be much lower by by the next year. So
we we already seen that with lipstick
like I don't know what was the
percentage of of of reduction with the
with the cost but we we we have already
seen that and and it's something that we
really believe like the next year the
cost will be much lower and with that it
will be profitable to to find bucks also
related to to hacker one um we we need
to say that we are not um using hackle
one as a way to uh you know to prove
that we can find bugs but more like a
playground to improve the the product.
So um of course having a lot of
different customers with different
applications and and use the using the
the the the networks and the the
environments to test and find bugs is
the best way to prove and to to to make
sure that our product is is improving.
So of course at the beginning when we
started we we couldn't find many of the
things that we can find nowadays and
hacker one has has helped us with with
that to improve the tool. So every day
we use that to whenever we we can um
detect a new vulnerability type we test
that in hacker one and we make sure that
we do all the improvements that we need.
So the so let's say that hack one is our
playground to to improve the tool.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that that seems like a great
way to address that. And and I wanted to
um address some of the, you know,
grumblings from the community where
they're saying, you know, Expo is just a
glorified XSS finder with all of the,
you know, I think it was like 800
reports or something like that from Expo
um of the 1100 are coming from XSS. And
furthermore, a lot of people are saying,
"Oh, Expo found this one like global
protect XSS and then just sprayed it
everywhere and that's like all 800 of
their reports." And I'm like, "Dude,
chill out." like that's definitely if
you could find 800 Inscope global
protect instances then the product rocks
but um what would you say to those
people? How would you address that
rumor? Yeah. So, so of course um and I
guess that you guys uh will will agree
with me. Um if you see someone in the
top leaderboard or hacker one, of
course, uh they they they are in in some
way uh finding a lot of the same stuff,
you know. Um of course maybe you'll be
like reporting a lot of subdomain
covers. You might be reporting a lot of
excss and that's something you cannot be
in the top if you don't report these
kind of bugs uh which are the most easy
to find. of course you won't see anyone
in the top leader finding reporting only
rce I mean
>> that that's not going to happen so of
course we we we need to to be clear with
that and and we are like excss is one of
the bugs that we can find u like more
often and of course we have a good way
as I was saying to validate them we have
like no uh false positives in excss so
whenever we find one we know that it's a
real one so so that's why one is is one
of the main issues that we we report
nowadays. But I have some numbers that I
got from from our hacker one stats and
during the three um three months that we
have been reporting stuff um we found
like more than I think it's 15 RC. So if
you ask to the top hackers of the
leaderboard how many RC they reported in
the
>> not 15 for me let me tell you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, so, so you know, of
course, we are reporting a lot of excss
because we we also find not only the
Palo Alto one, but a couple more COAs
that we still need to disclose, but uh
also all the reputation points that we
have are not coming from from XSS
because um mostly all the excss that we
have reported from from Palo Alto ended
up being informative because uh almost
nobody is accepting zero days in hiker.
one
>> right
>> uh so so we have a lot of informatives
we even have some NAS because companies
uh thought that we shouldn't be
reporting that and the first thing that
we did was report it to Palo Alto and
then of course we we we always think
that whenever like it's our
responsibility to to let the company
know so that they can also fix or add
some counter measures to fix that um
until of course Palato applies the the
the global
But yeah, uh I mean we have a lot of
different different reports. We have XXC
escal injection. We have 32 escal
injections during the last 90 days.
>> Uh dude,
>> I don't even have that in my own
account.
>> That's crazy.
>> So, so yeah, you can imagine that we we
are finding a lot of different bugs, but
of course, if you want to be in the top
in terms of reputation, you have to be
reporting these kind of bugs massively
as well.
>> Yeah, absolutely. all using any other
bug bounty platforms if you don't mind
me asking like I don't know if you all
were like running on
>> you know yes we hack or integrity or
anything right now
>> no I we have a few reports so we found
some also some sh days in some programs
that they had u the the they were in
other platforms like backrow and
intuitivity so we we also send the
reports to them but we are not like
actively reporting to to those platforms
you know
the the the we are not really interested
in the revenue from bounties. Uh we just
want to improve the tool. We just want
to uh make sure that the the the tool is
improving and I think that with hacker
one right now is more than enough and
they can give us everything that we need
to to like to improve the tool and and
we know that when the this like uh Palo
Alto was released a lot of people was
farming that in in background and we
don't care about that like we don't care
about that money we we just want to make
sure that we improve the the product.
>> Yeah. And and you mentioned XSS is kind
of one of the things that uh Expo can
find most reliably. And uh as I was
reading this write up of the the global
protect Texas test, I just wanted to say
I was I was impressed with some of the
methodology pieces here where you know
it looks particularly this part that I'm
sharing right now where it's looking at
the code and it's saying oh um test
results do not uh direct test results
showed that no direct reflections of our
XSS payloads were found. But we did
identify several JavaScript variables
that might be controllable through
mechanisms. and it lists a set of like
empty JavaScript variables that that uh
were sitting inside of a script tag or
something like that uh in the response
of this page. And I'm like, dude, that
is either the AI get getting that sort
of intuition, right, that the hacker
hacker thinks about, right? And and it
could be you guys, you know, putting
this in or it could be the AI developing
it itself. But uh I was impressed with
that because that's not, you know,
beginner as beginner tier stuff where
you see an empty JavaScript variable and
you're like, I bet I bet that if I take
that name and I put it in the query
parameter and I tweak it around a little
bit, maybe I can, you know, inject
directly into that context, which is one
of the most likely ones for XSS. Um, so
I'm going to ask, you know, directedly,
do you think that this is a um,
something that the AI sort of came up
with or is this the sort of thing that
you and Joel and all them are are sort
of building into the app this
methodology so that it can do stuff like
this?
>> Yeah. So, so this this is completely
from the AI.
>> Wow. That's that's interesting, man.
That it it it's using its brain, it's
using its creativity, right? Um, that's
that's exciting to see. It's really
crazy like in a in a few days we're
going to release a new bug uh probably
when this comes out will be released. Um
and and you know this uh this bag that
we are going to to publish is really
cool because it's it starts using
information that has from the training
data set and it finds a bug by doing
some combinations of parameters that it
knows and some endpoints that it knows
and then it finds a a bug in a product
that is widely used like lot of
companies is using. um
>> is super crazy when you see that
>> and and I guess I should ask I guess a
little bit more clearly about that last
question like not to say that that would
be bad at all, right? Like that is your
job is to make this AI better. So like
to to what degree are you guys involved
you know as top tier security
researchers how how are you involved in
building the prompting that powers these
these bots? Because you know I would
imagine that if you hadn't told it hey
uh if you see an empty JavaScript
variable try to put that in the query
parameter and see if you can reflect
into it then that would be like a pretty
you know you instead of relying on the
AI for that if you put that in the
prompting then the AI you know I imagine
would increase its methodology a lot
more. So are you guys sort of involved
in developing that methodology that
you're feeding into the AI or are you
contributing in some other way? Yeah. So
we we are in charge of like uh
developing these sort of technical
prompts. So uh you know if you ask the
AI to find let's say XSS, it will
probably end up uh trying like the
typical XSS techniques but it will
probably forget about uh trying the
serial uh techniques or it would
probably don't test for post message or
it would probably don't try for stored
XSS. So, so of course that kind of
things are are something that we are we
are working right now and we are adding
that information into the prompt so that
we force the the the solvers to find and
try that specific techniques. So that's
something that we we are working on and
and but yeah that example that you were
showing like that exactly uh example is
not something that we have provided. I
think that's just something from from
the entirely
>> that's crazy. So, do you uh this is a
question you had, Justin, but I'm going
to go ahead and say it. Do you think
that like we would just love to have
your opinion and your take on like
humans in the loop? Like I think that
you're obviously mentioning lots of
stuff that you're impressed by where
there basically are no humans in the
loop and you all are driving false
positive rates down to zero where
automated reporting would actually even
work out. Those two things to me scream
like, hey, actually, you should be
mildly worried cuz like we might not
need humans in the loop at all, right?
But um but you know clearly having you
all to do like final triage, final
validation is like very um valuable at
Expo and you know I personally think
that other hackbot companies will need
um you know hackers to write those
technical prompts that you were just
talking about and for doing that last
layer of validation and testing. But uh
anyways, yeah, I would just be curious
one like if there's like a product
strategy or vision like do you like you
know obviously you haven't said this but
it would be extremely beneficial if you
had access to expo to just use for your
bug for your bug bounty on the side
right and I'm sure you're not allowed to
use it for that but like if you were it
would be amazing and uh you know me and
Justin need access so we can find more
vulnerabilities of course but no but no
in general you know like I would just
love your thoughts on like human in the
loop versus not human in the loop both
as like where is the industry heading
But then maybe more importantly like
does Expo plan to potentially you know
have bug bounty drivers uh you know
running Expo for customers at any point
or if you're able to share that or not.
I would definitely love to have all your
thoughts on all of that.
>> Yeah. Okay. So regarding uh autonomous
agents versus human in the loop I think
that both uh approaches are valid and
complimentary in some ways like Expo is
fully focused on full autonomy. So that
was what we are looking for. Uh we are
not including any human in the loop. Uh
besides what we are doing right now like
for improving the tool. Um right now the
only thing that we are doing is just
getting the report checking that it's a
right report and sending it to hacker
one uh whenever is is is a good one. But
uh for customers we are not even doing
that. Like all the things that we
provide is fully autonomous like the
reports, the findings everything. Uh but
of course I still think that human in
the loop is something that uh is is
interesting but I don't think that
scales way well well like um it brings
value of course in some cases because
you can use that human intu intuition
and creativity to to like improve how
the how the AI behaves. But we think
that there are some ways to do that
without having a human. you know they
have some things in in mind for the
future and how to combine both without
having any human interaction and still
using uh like our knowledge and our
creativity. Uh but yeah, in our case, we
are fully focused on fully autonomy and
it's something that we are.
>> Yeah,
>> I mean I think that I think that that
long-term vision is probably why Expo
has best done so well. Like I think if
you keep that goal in mind as you build
a product like Expo is building then
you're going to end up with the best
product in the end, you know, whereas
like like you're if you're already kind
of like coping out and like falling back
on humans like along the way in multiple
steps, then you're then you know that's
not like the ideal end state for it. So
but that is really interesting and kind
of scary. Yeah. Justin, what do you
think?
>> Yeah, I'm I'm I'm thinking about that
man. And I think I think my intuition my
thought is that human in the loop is
going to be bigger for the next couple
years and then it may take off from
there into into autonomous. Obviously we
haven't seen really uh a big player in
the space that's working on human in in
the loop. Uh as much as I've you know
that I've heard of at least maybe Joseph
you've got some inside uh scoop or some
uh uh you know NDA stuff you can't talk
about. I I do know some companies that
are leaning that way for sure, but I
mean clearly we don't see the results on
the leaderboard, right? So, right, my
word to them would be get on the
leaderboards.
>> Yeah, exactly. I think I think it's a a
massive proof, you know, that Expo is
performing well. So, definitely congrats
on that. I I did want to loop back
around to the prompting thing, though.
You know, you guys are spending your
time building out these prompts that
optimize the AI's performance going up
against these targets. And I I wonder if
you have any advice to the um you know
the bug bounty hunter or the the
pentester that will be writing their own
prompts um for human in the loop uh
automation
and I'm not sure whether you can share
it or not but any takeaways you can have
would be helpful.
>> Um yeah I don't know too what to say
about that. Um
>> yeah I'm not sure if I understood the
question. I think he's saying from like
from like a meta level like when you're
going into like let's say you let's say
they added support and expo to like
really search for I don't know CSS
injection to try to leak credit card
numbers right like Justin's favorite bug
or whatever. And so if you're if you
were going to go in and write like a
system prompt for that specific attack
technique like what are the things that
you hold in your mind like the ideas
that like you know result in like a good
prompt for a specific attack vector?
Is that what you're asking Justin? Oh
yeah, it's mo it's mostly about prompt
engineering for security, right? Like
what things have you learned, Diego?
Because I'm sure you know your position
in Expo, you're one of the top experts
on this, I'm sure, you know, uh what
have you learned about prompt
engineering that gets the AI to give
better results and I'm asking you a
little bit to give out the secret sauce,
right? A little bit here. So in as much
detail as you can share, um what are
your thoughts on that? Yeah. So, so
something that I can tell is that um as
far as you provide as many details as
possible, the eye will perform better
like you know and that's something
related to what I was talking before
like if you just give like a very
generic uh description of what you are
looking for let's say XSS and you don't
provide like a specific techniques to
test. I don't know if it's something
related on how uh models are are made
but the DI will start testing like the
typical payloads and it will forget
about testing the really complex stuff.
So if you add that kind of information
like hey remember to test this or hey
remember to like you can try this other
technique we can see that from time to
time it would try that and it will
prioritize that instead of just trying
like normal payloads and spamming that
all around. So that that's some some of
the tips that that I learned like if
you're very specific and also if you
provide like a very specific endpoint to
test a very specific type of issue, it
performs much better than if you just
give freedom and and and let him like
>> as much technical detail as possible
there I guess is interesting. And are
you how do you balance that? And I'm not
sure if this is your department. Maybe
you just show up and say this is the the
methodology like figure out how to fit
it into a prompt. But uh some of the
things that um Joseph and I have
struggled with with AI you know
engineering from our side with shift and
and other AI products is balancing you
know oh I want to give a lot of examples
I want to give a thorough prompt with
prompt size and how much that reduces
your context of also getting information
from the AI itself and getting that into
the prompt. Um have you faced that or is
your like superpowered AI team kind of
dealt with all that for you? Yeah. So to
be honest, uh I've created some prompts
myself, but of course there's people in
the team much better than I uh doing
that. So whenever I try like whenever I
want to focus in some specific type of
issue, I'll just like develop a problem
that I will use and then I pass it to
the AI team and they will do some
adjustments to fix that and they would
came up with some recommendations like
if you use this instead of this it will
likely perform better. So they have all
that knowledge to improve those prompts
and I just provide like the techniques
of the things that we want to test or
the the specific attack types that we
want to to test.
>> So that's that's really cool that that
you get to sort of collaborate with
other experts in that in that arena like
that and condense that information.
>> Um I did want to circle back around to
the post message based stuff. Um
obviously I love post messagebased
stuff. It's one of the things that I I
test for a lot and I think that it would
be really hard to test for post message
based vulnerabilities without um at
least for a human without access to a
debugger. So I'm wondering what your
harness for expo looks like in a post
message testing environment.
>> Yeah. So that's something is really cool
that you asked because it's something
that we have been uh report starting to
report recently like one week ago
something like that. Um so we have like
so we have some some tools uh one of one
of them is a a headlight browser that is
included. I forgot to mention that but
we have a head browser also included as
part of the tooling that we provide to
the AI. So, so of course we can use the
the browser to test and to to interact
with the application and then we have
included some sort of uh features so
that we can um also show the ever
listeners. We can show the DOM content.
We can show all that information from
the the from the console and the debug
so that the AI knows what happening in
in in in the client side as well. So, so
whenever we we ask expo to find the post
message base uh vulnerabilities, we we
have some sort of um version that that
provides this information to the server
and with that it it's it finds all the
all the stuff.
>> Okay. So, is it utilizing a debugger
itself or is it mostly looking at the
DOM and the console logs?
>> It's it's doing it's looking at the at
the DOM and the console logs. Yeah.
>> Okay. Solid. Yeah, that's that's uh it
would be very interesting to have it,
you know, be able to set break points at
various points and inspect the state,
but that would be such a complicated
thing to code. Like I imagine that's
going to be way down the line. Um
>> yeah, and I think that that's something
that definitely in the future we may
have. Right now we don't have that, but
it's something that we may have in the
future. Yeah.
>> Very cool. Yeah. And so, you know, it
it's shooting off a payload, you know,
it's observing what kind of stuff is
coming coming back from that and just
from that back and forth and code
auditing, it's trying to craft the
payload that will result in the in the
vulnerability.
>> Yeah, exactly. And then we have also the
XV hosting like the hosting service to
like uh store any any any HTML with a PC
so that then it can reproduce it with a
>> Yeah.
>> Is is is this implemented uh with Chrome
DevTools protocol? Is that what you guys
are using to hook into all of this or do
you have some other Do you have like a
custom browser build or what?
>> No, we we are using Chrome. Yeah,
>> Chrome DevTools protocol. Okay,
>> gotcha. Nice.
>> Well, make sure you keep it up to date
so we don't have a uh
>> what's it called? A reverse prompt
injection execution on the Expo
executor.
>> Yeah. Well, I was actually going to ask
him about that, dude, because if you
look at the global protect write up, it
says, "Okay, I'm getting the get
config.esp endpoint, right? Uh Richard,
there's a a um image in the thing. If
you could put it up on the screen at
this point, that'd be great. Um but you
know, it does a curl request, right? It
just says pentester zero and it does a
curl request out uh and then it parses
the result with um XML lint, right? And
and I'm like, "Oh, wow. It's dynamically
generating like dash, you know, like I
kind of want to do an argument injection
right here." Like, you know, like, have
you ever seen, you know, it trigger
syntax errors or are you guys concerned
about sort of reverse hacking uh when
using Expo as a product?
>> Yeah, so that's something also uh is
something that we have been working as
well like protecting and and making sure
that we don't execute something that we
don't want to do to execute. Yeah,
>> and of course all the instances that we
are using for testing are completely
isolated. So even though we have any
case that we didn't have yet, but even
though we have any case in the future of
some problem injection that of course is
always there and could happen um we we
we have like this this isolated
environment. So we don't have any any
issues and that's like completely that's
not connected to any component from from
Exo or or or connected to the
infrastructure. So in that aspect is is
well like everything is uh ephemereral.
So so so that's great but of course we
we are improving that like we improving
the the safe. It'd be interesting if a
company was like, "All right, run Expo
on us, right?" And then they give get a
reverse shell on Expo and then Expo's
like, "Oh, I found this vulnerability."
And they're like, "That's not good." You
know, like like they get the free
assessment because they shelled Expo and
just dumped whatever was on there and
it's like, "Yeah,
>> oh [__] Six findings. That's not good."
>> Um,
>> do not give ideas to the people, please.
>> Yeah,
don't do that. Not endorsed by by
Critical Thinking Podcast. Um, wow,
dude. Well, you know, overall I've been
really impressed by it. Um, you know,
the the results. The only other big
question that we had here was like you
you have been interacting with the the
bug bounty platforms and through the um
how do I how do I phrase this? Through
the uh you know network of bug bounty
hunters that we have access to with
critical thinking. We've seen um a
couple hackers have mentioned that there
are some programs updating their scope
saying you know ex expo AI has been
ignoring our guidelines and have
submitted a couple hundred test cases or
you know whatever. Um have you run into
a lot of programs where the AI is going
rogue and you got to be like sorry about
that. I mean that's a part of bug bounty
right that's going to be a part of what
people sign up for when they go onto
these programs but um I'm wondering the
frequency of that and how you guys have
dealt with that. Yeah. So as I was
saying before we we have some um
infrastructure on top of all our product
um that makes sure that the scope that
we are testing is is the right one. Of
course in this case that you are
mentioning uh it was a company that they
have one application which was in scope
and and it found Expo found an
application that has like some form with
a capture that wasn't working properly.
So, Expo managed to bypass that and then
started submitting like uh forms uh over
and over again and it seems that we we
ended up like submitting a lot of
support cases.
>> Was wasn't that in Burp 17 too? Like the
spider would have like the automated
like form submission. Guys, you all
won't believe this. At my old employer,
I was running that on a prod system and
it was creating objects everywhere. It
was like it was blowing up the database.
I was running just that old form. I was
like spidering on the old burp with like
just like the all no safety protocols.
Oh, it was a mess. So, anyways. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Of course, we didn't have
like too many cases uh where we where we
had issues with customers. Of course, we
have we had some I would be lying if we
if I said the the the opposite. Um but
also I think that you know in in every
uh in every test that we perform we are
sending the X bounty header with expo
name. Uh so it's also easy for the
companies to know that we are uh doing
that kind of testing. So I'm really sure
that other people with their automation
are also poking those applications and
might be even broken breaking them. Uh
but then if they check the the logs and
they see expo, they might be pointing to
us.
>> Yeah, that's a good that's a good point,
Diego, is that you guys are doing it
responsibly and in a way that's easily
correlated back to you and other bug
bounty hunters for sure are not,
>> you know. So maybe you're taking the
heat a little bit, but that's because
you're being intentional about it.
>> Yeah. So So now all we have to do,
Justin, is just start using XBounty Expo
in our heads.
>> Yeah. The other day was a customer that
was asking to us like, "Hey, are you uh
like using this IP address to test this
application and we had to check and it
was an XO but um you know they they they
have been they saw that header in one of
other applications in the logs and they
thought that we may be also uh testing
the other application. So so yeah but in
our case we are always um sending this
header. So whenever someone has any
doubts you can check that and see if etc
or no and we are using like a very
specific header so that no one's can can
use it.
>> Oh that's actually a good point. Yeah
you can use like
>> and we are also changing that like we
can set like a different header.
>> Nice.
>> Um every day. So so yeah.
>> Wow. Very cool. I I have gone through
here. I think I've got all of my expo
questions out of the way. Uh Joseph, you
got any other ones? I could probably go
on uh for a lot longer. And also, it's
hard for me not to like I I'm just like
restraining myself to not ask stuff that
would be like too sensitive because I
obviously want to know all the details,
but I think that that would also be like
I think that Diego's been extremely
extremely open and forthcoming. And I
think one that's really cool that you
all do that like even publishing those
traces are something that I think the
majority of companies would not do. Like
even just showing that like the primary
tool usage is Python, right? but it can
also do, you know, custom full request
and then the fact that you're sharing
more about the harnesses and other stuff
and like so I I one I mean you all
probably have that privilege to do that
because you feel like you are kind of so
far ahead um or or maybe you all just as
a company really believe in kind of um
you know information sharing in general
to kind of push the industry further and
increase the security of everything. Um
I do want to I think this could be a
pretty scary conversation for a lot of
listeners. So I actually I do want to
take a quick second here to basically
tell people like at the end of the day
like the security of everything is going
to get much more improved by stuff like
this. And I and I do think that
I I kind of fully agree with Justin that
I think kind of human in the loop will
still do well for years. Um, and I think
there are still lots and lots of
multi-step vulnerabilities like the the
the ATO that Diego mentioned at the
beginning. Like there's not going to be
a hackbot that's going to find anything
remotely close to that for years. U like
it will find other things that are
similarly impressive but not things that
require multiple bypasses and XSS on a
different site and all of that. Like I
think that that's still years incoming.
And um I saw a really nice tweet from um
really nice tweet from Simon Willis
today that said like saying that you're
going to give up on coding because LLMs
exist is like a carpenter saying they're
going to give up on carpentry just
because a table saw was invented. And I
think that's I think that's a really
great analogy for hacking too. It's like
hey you know just because these amazing
you know AI hacking applications are
being developed doesn't mean that you
need to give up on the industry because
it would be kind of silly to do that at
this point. So anyways,
>> yeah, I I agree. Any any thoughts you
want to add about that, Diego? Or can I
pick your brain a little bit more about
the AWC stuff?
>> Yeah, so so I agree with I fully agree
with with with Reso. I think that um of
course uh doing like complex chaining
nowadays for is complex and we all know
that. But we we've so far like from one
year until now we we saw like a huge
improvement in in models and we we
started seeing kind of similar behavior
in in in that. Um and we we have some
findings where we like we saw that the
the the solvers were chaining multiple
bugs uh and like starting exploiting
SSRF and chaining that with a local
inclusion and we saw that in in our
traces and we are willing to to share
that soon. So I guess that for now we we
are safe uh and and always uh human will
be necessary for for some specific kind
of bugs but in the time we will see. I
think that it's going to get like bigger
and bigger. So
>> I think so too. A lot of these more
simple bugs may disappear. Um so that's
why why it's definitely smart for for uh
you know people to scale up a little bit
here and start looking for more complex
vulnerabilities even if you're able to
pay your bills with authorization
vulnerabilities, right? You know or XSS
or whatever um or simple XSS I should
say because there's some complicated XSS
out there. But um definitely a time to
start looking for more complex chains
and and getting those reps in to to find
those. Um all right. Well, I I did want
to come back to the AWC because I'm a
little salty about it, not going to lie.
Like like I just I wanted to love it. I
really did. I wanted to love it, but I
just don't don't think it's there. Um
obviously you guys did really well. We
talked about it a little bit in the
beginning, you know, uh that this is the
second year in a row that you guys have
won it. Um, I think if you do win
something twice, we see a pattern,
right? You know, um, I'm wondering
whether you guys are going to go as him
on it next year. Are you going to try as
hard next year? Um, with the AWC if
nothing changes, uh, or are you guys
going to sit it out?
>> Yeah. So, I think that definitely we are
going to go for the fair one. I mean,
like all the people from
>> Yeah. All the people from Spain are like
super try hard with with these kind of
competitions. they really like winning
and also um I think it's uh it's that
time of the year where the people you
know we were talking about this before
like um and you can see that for example
gojo one of the top one uh hackers in in
in hacker one he's one of the most
dedicated hackers in in this competition
and and you know he has like a lot of
bounties and even even though it it
spends a lot of time this competition as
well so it's like a way to share time
with with all uh people the team we are
like close friends we have like a really
good relation and we like to collaborate
we like uh like going traveling together
and that's one of the main things that I
think uh one of the reasons why Spain is
doing like really well like everyone is
in in the same uh in the same mood and
and we are collaborating with with each
other and yeah I think that's definitely
something that is is It's like the
secret sauce. That's what I was saying.
>> Well, the real secret sauce is if
they're struggling, Justin, they just
tap in Expo and then, you know, just
>> Yeah, dude. I I think that commitment
piece is is really big, right? You know,
one of the the things you keep saying,
you know, about Team Spain is how
committed they are, right? And I think
that it's hard to get that many people
rallied behind a shared vision.
>> Um, so that's a that's a big achievement
for sure. Um and and I think it's also
hard for people to um you know motivate
themselves to push push push hard um you
on something like this uh for an
extended period of time because this is
multiple competitions back to back to
back.
>> Um so yeah I think that's exciting to
see with with the the nuts and bolts of
collaboration you know do you have any
tips on that Team Spain has used to
optimize their collaboration between
other hackers and how do you guys deal
with bounty splits? So two questions
there. Yeah. So, uh something that we
you we do like in every round of this
competition is that usually we have a
couple teams of two or three people like
uh we do like mini teams inside team
Spain and we we we split like the scope
that we we have. So let's say that we
have three or four companies. So we
start doing like teams of two or three
people and we go through different
scopes and that's a way to don't have
duplicates against us like itself
because in the first rounds we have
duplicates inside the team as well and
and it's funny because even even though
we had some duplicates
uh I remember that some of the team were
even inviting the other teammates like
hey you find this I find it before I
will invite you to the to the report uh
with a 50/50 which is like
>> insane and I saw bad inside the team and
I I don't think that other uh people in
other teams are doing the same and in
the end I think that happened because we
because we are also friends and and
that's like really really important.
>> Do you all get together physically like
there are there a lot of you all near
Madrid?
>> Uh not really. I think we are a couple a
couple members in in Madrid. Some are in
Barcelona. Some are not even in in in
Spain are in Portugal nearby in Spain.
Um but yeah, from time to time we we try
to travel and do at least one of the
rounds uh together. I think that this
year we had uh we meet up in two
different rounds uh and then we have
like the quarterfinals which was in
Prague and then the finals in in Dubai.
So we we meet each other like four four
rounds.
>> So that's also important as well.
>> Obviously we didn't experience those
last few rounds. Did the last few rounds
end up um slightly better with the lack
of like a way lower numbers? Like it's
not as as harsh on duplicates and you
know payouts or bonuses and stuff. How
did that look?
>> Yeah, it was a bit better because uh you
know I think that also customers were
better like in those rounds. Um, and
it's also something that I was was uh
willing to talk in this in this podcast.
Like I think that not all the customers
from this competition are mature enough
to uh to be part of this competition. I
know I know that some customers were
like really overwhelmed with reports and
they even don't know how uh this
competition works. They don't know that
they have to do triage in time. They
they don't know that they have to pay in
time. So I don't I think that this is
something that definitely hack one has
to improve. They have to try to look for
customers that are mature enough and
they know how this works. But in the
other side I know that it's hard also
for them to find customers that they
want to participate of course. So yeah
they have to balance between those.
>> Yeah dude that's that that is definitely
a balance. Um, but it's I mean I think
the the targets are going to they're
signing up for a lot, you know, when
they when they go onto this, you know,
especially I think it takes a lot of
guts to say like, "All right, 600 and
blahy blah hackers just
>> come at us." Um, but it definitely takes
a level of maturity. So hopefully um H1
will nail that down and and in the
future as they continue to grow the AWC,
you know, hopefully they'll have more of
like a brief or whatever of like this is
what you could expect like buckle up
sort of scenario as well.
>> Yeah, I remember something really good
that Hacker one did in a final. So when
the competition ended, they did some
like one hour feedback uh on site. So
they they got all the teams together and
we start like talking about the the
whole competition giving feedback to
hacker one. So I think that's really
really smart for for for doing that
>> and hopefully they they will get get
some advices for for the next year and
but yeah in the end I think that
everything depends on customers. If
customers are good enough uh I think
that the round should be good. Also I
think that they have to do some changes
with the teams. I don't think that they
there should be um countries with five
or six teams. It doesn't make sense.
There's a lot of people in the end
poking at the same targets and that's
something also that is bad.
>> So do you think do you think the team
should be limited to one per country and
then capped at a certain size? Is that
what you're thinking?
>> Yeah, I think so. and and it's something
that we are trying to do in Spain like
in Spain we are two different
ambassadors uh Hypothermia and me and we
were asking multiple uh times like we we
wanted to split the team and we always
said that we prefer to have one team
with 20 people that that that are fully
uh committed to to the competition
instead of having like five teams of
people that in the end they're not going
to spend enough time and that's also
something that we that I think is is is
working good for us and we are rotating
the team. Whenever we have someone that
is not like doesn't have time enough to
to spend uh we are fully transparent
like if you don't have time to spend
there's always someone that wants to get
into the team. So also that's working
really good for us.
>> That's awesome man. That's awesome. Well
it's definitely been a success for for
team Spain. It's been exciting to see.
Um, yeah, I I think collaboration at
that scale is really challenging even,
you know, when you've got the two teams
or if if it, you know, it's just one big
team of 20 people. So, I'm excited to
see how it'll it'll pan out in the
future.
>> Um, all right, Joseph, I mean, that's
all I had on the docket. Did Did you
have anything else you wanted to ask of?
>> No, I'm super grateful and super
thankful for your time, Diego. Um, and
for your Yeah. just being willing to
answer our questions and even come on
here. So, we're
>> Yeah. Um, did you have anything you
wanted to shout out at the end here,
Diego, or something you wanted to get on
the record for the pod?
>> Uh, not really. I I appreciate that you
have invited me. Uh, it's been really
amazing to talk with you guys. So, yeah,
thank you for that and looking forward
for for a a new like uh podcast in the
future maybe.
>> Yeah, dude. We love that.
>> That sounds great, man. That sounds
great. All right. Peace. That's the pod.
>> See you guys.
>> Thank you.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.